Okay, I'm going to choose a really big font, and
では一番大きいフォントを選んだ後に
then I'll try a really small font.
一番小さいフォントを選んでみます
So I picked display three here, which is 56sp.
56spで表示された Display３を選びます
And remember to, add an attribute before the tag is closed.
タグを閉じる前に属性を 追加することを忘れずに
So I'll hit enter here and then add textSize attribute.
Enterを押して textSizeの属性を追加します
Cool.
よし
And then the text is giant over here.
文字が巨大に表示されましたね
Now I can try a smaller size, of maybe some body text
bodyの部分テキストを 小さくしてみましょう
which would be 14 SP, so I'll erase this and
14spにします こちらを消します
then say 14, and then it's tiny again, cool.
14と入力すると また小さくなりました
Okay, so we finished the first task.
最初の課題ができました
The optional challenge was to try learning about the text appearance
おまけの課題はリンクを貼った Google Plus Pro tipから―
attribute on your own from the Google Plus protip that I included a link to.
自分でテキストの表示 属性を覚えることです
Let's open that up now.
見てみましょう
So, this is an Android dev protip that was written by yours truly, for
Android デベロッパーの Google Plus ページのために
the Android developers Google Plus page.
私が書いた AndroidデベロッパーPro tip です
If you haven't already, you can follow the Google Plus page for
Android開発について 最新ニュースを得るために
Android developers, to get the latest news on Android development.
Google Plusのページを フォローすることもできます
Or if you'd prefer Twitter, you can follow our account there.
Twitterの方が良ければ 私たちのアカウントをフォローできます
So basically in this short pro tip, I talk about
ここで話していることは
So you can use the recommended font sizes in the Material Design spec, or
マテリアルデザイン仕様で 推奨されている文字サイズを使ったり
you can also choose from a standard set of type sizes, provided by Android,
Andoroidが提供する 標準サイズから選ぶことができます
which is small, medium and large.
小さい 普通 大きいサイズがあります
So instead of text size, you said the Android TextAppearance attribute
文字サイズを指定する代わりに Android TextAppearanceに
to be androidTextAppearanceLarge, or you can set small or medium.
“androidTextAppearanceLarge”としたり small mediumと指定できます
These TextAppearance values map to these SP font sizes.
このTextAppearanceの値は SPのサイズが当てられます
So with these ever changing Android
Androidに変化があったとしても―
then your code will automatically get the new value.
コードは自動的に新しい値を入手できます
Using text appearance is grea,t because you don't have to worry about specific
text appearanceは SP値をつける心配がないですし
you can still be consistent with other apps on the device.
デバイス上で他のアプリとも サイズを合わせることができます
For example, for a title you can use large, for
例えばタイトルには大きいサイズを使い
a list item you can use medium, or for a caption you can use small.
リストには普通のサイズ 説明文には小さいサイズを使います
So these are good buckets to work with.
これを利用すると便利です
You can try the mat in our code by copying this line here.
この一列をコピーしてコードに使えます
You can use cmd+Ccor you can use ctrl+c if you're on a Windows machine.
Macならcommand＋C Windowsならctrl＋Cでコピーします
Go over to our code here.
コードへ移動します
I'm going to delete this text size line,
文字サイズの一列を消します
because we're going to add text appearance.
text appearanceを使いますので
Hit command V or control V.
command＋Vまたはctrl＋Vで貼り付け
So now android text appearance is text appearance large.
android text appearanceは text appearance largeです
And you can see that the preview has updated to have the larger font size.
プレビューで文字サイズが 大きくなったことが確認できます
That's pretty neat, right?
便利ですよね？
And you can also change this to be medium or small.
medium にもsmallにも変えられます
So in general, this is really useful to know,
知っておくと とても便利です
if you don't want to declare specific SP values.
具体的なSP値を指定しなくて済みます
So if you have no idea which SP values you want to use,
SP値がいくつになるのか 決まっていなければ―
you can just pick from small, medium, large.
small medium largeから選べばいいのです